Guide to the Amsterdam News photograph archive, Series A. Subject Files P-T, 1920-2012.
Amsterdam News photograph archive
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Amsterdam News photograph archive, 1920-2012.
8084
New York Amsterdam News.
189 cubic feet.
Correspondence, Photographs, Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection includes photographs and related materials covering a broad range of topics, with a particular focus on day-to-day life in New York's African-American community during the 20th century.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Founded in 1909 by James H. Anderson, the New York Amsterdam News is one of the oldest African-American owned and run newspapers in the country. Initially focused on local news in New York in general and Harlem in particular, the Amsterdam News broadened its scope to include national news under the guidance of editor Dr. C.B. Powell in the 1930s. By the 1960s, the newspaper had become a major voice in the national African-American community, offering extensive coverage of the civil rights movement. Beginning in 1982, the newspaper was edited by Wilbert A. Tatum, under whose guidance the newspaper remained a voice in local and national affairs. In 1996, Tatum turned control of the newspaper over to his daughter, Elinor Tatum, who remained the publisher and editor-in-chief through the 2000s.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection includes photographs and related materials covering a broad range of topics, with a particular focus on day-to-day life in New York's African-American community during the 20th century. Subjects include civil rights marches and protests, church events, high school graduations, local politics, and fashion. Some photographs were taken by staff photographers, while others originated with wire services or as submissions from individuals or agencies. Formats in the collection include silver gelatin prints, negatives (including many unpublished images), contact sheets, Polaroids, wire photos, and halftone prints. As the working photo archive of a continuously-published newspaper, many of the images have retouching, attached captions, press releases, cover letters, and printer's instructions. In addition to photographs, the collection includes ephemera and manuscript material, including newspaper article drafts, typescript and mimeographed speeches, correspondence, event programs, magazine and newspaper clippings, employment applications, press releases, and newspaper production materials.
The bulk of the materials in the archive range from the mid-1940s through the mid-1990s. The materials are divided into series, reflecting the organization of the materials in the AM News offices. A major sub-series of the collection is the archive of Mel Tapley, who began working for the Amsterdam News in 1942 and served as entertainment editor until his retirement in 1997. The Mel Tapley archive includes a wide variety of material, including correspondence, manuscript and typescript articles and notes, artwork, press kits, publicity photos, and printing plates for comic strips drawn by Tapley.
Photographers represented in the collection include Bert Andrews, Kwame Brathwaite, Al Burley, James C. Campbell, Curt Clemons, Juanita M. Cole, Karl Crutchfield, L. St. Clair Dummett, Monroe S. Frederick II, James Gilbert, Dave Greene, Austin Hansen, Tex Harris, Bob Head, Cecil Layne, David McAdams, Bill Moore, Allen Morgan, Vondel Nichols, Lem Peterkin, George M. West, and Lloyd Yearwood. Photo agencies and services represented include Pictorial Enterprise, Wide World Photo, Harris Photo, News Voice International, Rapid News Photo, United Press International, Negro Press Photo Service, Wagner International Photos, and Ace Creative Photos.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York Amsterdam News.
Titles:
New York Amsterdam news.
Subjects:
African American newspapers.; African Americans -- New York (State) -- New York.
Places:
New York (N.Y.); Harlem (New York, N.Y.)
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Because of the size of this collection, the guide is broken up into several different pages. Each page is then further separated into different series. The majority of the sereis titles come from titles given by the Amsterdam News.
Main Guide Content Listing
Series A. Main photo sequence
The main alphabetic sequence of prints containing material from 1920-2012 with the bulk being 1944-1996.
Subject files A
Subject files B
Subject files C
Subject files D
Subject files E
Subject files F
Subject files G
Subject files H
Subject files I
Subject files J
Subject files K
Subject files L
Subject files M
Subject files N
Subject files O
Subject files P
Subject files Q
Subject files R
Subject files S
Subject files T
Subject files U
Subject files V
Subject files W
Subject files X
Subject files Y
Subject files Z
Series B. Inactive File
File of inactive, defunct, or deceased individuals and organizations. Bulk material dates from before 1980.
Series C. Presorted Photos
A roughly sorted series of photos.
Series D. Semi Alphabetized Photos
A second roughly sorted series of photos. Most date from 1980-1999.
Series E. Dated Folders
Photos from the 1990s sorted by date.
Series F. Sports Photos
Mostly promotional photos from sports teams.
Series G. Contemporary File
An alphabetic sequence of photos primarily from 1988-2000, but with some older material.
Series H. Transfer File
An alphabetic sequence of topical files with bulk material dates from the 1960s-1970s.
Series I. Dead Photo File
Photos from the 2000s organized by date of their publication in the Amsterdam News.
Series J. Loose Unsorted Items
Unsorted items found in various locations around the Amsterdam News office.
Series MT. Mel Tapley Collection
The personal archive of Mel Tapley, who began working at the Amsterdam News in 1942 and served as the entertainment editor until 1997. Includes a wide variety of ephemera, artwork, manuscript and typescript material, and correspondence.
Miscellaneous Mailings and Press Files
Mel Tapley Artwork
Unsorted Photos
Press Mailings
Books and Booklets
Press Kits
Press Releases
Oversize and Fax Press Releases
Periodicals, Newspapers, Magazines
Audio and Visual Media
CONTAINER LIST
- Series A. Subject Files A
  - Subject Files P
    - Pabon, Roselin (Box A-92, Folder 89)
      Number of Prints: 1
    - Pace Brothers (Box A-92, Folder 90)
      1 velox print.
    - Pace, H. A. Stuart II (Box A-92, Folder 91)
      Also press release.
    - Pace, Henry (Box A-92, Folder 92)
      Photographer if identified: Harris Photo
    - Pace, Jean (Box A-92, Folder 93)
      Number of Prints: 4
    - Pace, John (Box A-92, Folder 94)
    - Pace, Judy (Box A-92, Folder 95)
      Also one velox print.
      Number of Prints: 10
    - Pace Setters Club (Box A-92, Folder 96)
      Photographer if identified: James Gilbert, Pictorial Enterprise
      Number of Prints: 3
    - Pace University (Box A-92, Folder 97)
      1 print has a staple through edge.
      Photographer if identified: Ira Allen, Raymond Ross,
    - Pace, William & Irma (Box A-92, Folder 98)
      Photographer if identified: Lloyd Yearwood
    - Pacheco, Johnny (Box A-92, Folder 99)
    - Pachter, Irwin (Box A-92, Folder 100)
      Print has press release stapled to verso.
    - Pachter, Jacob (Box A-92, Folder 101)
    - Pachwood, Cyril O. (Box A-92, Folder 102)
    - Pacino, Al (Box A-92, Folder 103)
    - Packard, Jack (Box A-92, Folder 104)
      Number of Prints: 2
    - Packwood, Cyril O. (Box A-92, Folder 105)
      Photographer if identified: Pach Bros.
    - PACT (Box A-92, Folder 106)
      Number of Prints: 6
    - Padgett, James A. Prof. (Box A-92, Folder 107)
      Photographer if identified: Wagner International Photos
    - Padgett, John Bishop (Box A-92, Folder 108)
      Print is a Polaroid.
    - Padgette, Jim (See Earl Robinson) (Box A-92, Folder 109)
    - Padmone, George (Box A-92, Folder 110)
    - Padmore, Geo. A (Box A-92, Folder 111)
      Print has staples through edge.
      Photographer if identified: Pan American World Airways
    - Padmore, Wilford (Box A-92, Folder 112)
    - Padron, Lula B. (Box A-92, Folder 113)
    - Padrano, Donato (Box A-92, Folder 114)
    - Pagan, Anna (Box A-92, Folder 115)
    - Pagan, Antonio (Box A-92, Folder 116)
      Photographer if identified: Karl Crutchfield
    - Pagan, Bruni (Box A-92, Folder 117)
      Photographer if identified: Albert Watson
    - Pagan, D. (Box A-92, Folder 118)
      Photographer if identified: Rodriguez Photo Studio
    - Pagan, Richard Mrs. (Box A-92, Folder 119)
      Photographer if identified: Loring Studios
    - Pagan, Wordie (Box A-92, Folder 120)
      Photographer if identified: N.Y. Daily News Photo
    - Page, Ken (Box A-92, Folder 121)
      Photographer if identified: J. Richard Colbert,
    - Page, LaWanda (Box A-92, Folder 122)
      Photographer if identified: Cleveland Davies,
    - Page, Leon (Box A-92, Folder 123)
      Print is taped to cardboard.
      Photographer if identified: Jim Brown
    - Page, Linda (Box A-92, Folder 124)
      3 prints stapled together with ms. Leaf on verso.
      Photographer if identified: Photos by Luigi, Photography by Wilson, Harris Photo, James Gilbert,
      Number of Prints: 16
    - Page, Patti (Box A-92, Folder 125)
    - Page, Sheila (Box A-92, Folder 126)
    - Page, Sonia (Box A-92, Folder 127)
    - Page, Valerie (Box A-92, Folder 128)
      Photographer if identified: Trans World Air Lines
    - Page, Wally (Box A-92, Folder 129)
      Print has newspaper clipping taped to verso.
      Photographer if identified: Gilbert Pictorial Enterprise
    - Pageants (Black) (Box A-92, Folder 130)
    - Paiewonsky, Ralph M. (Box A-92, Folder 131)
    - Paige, Anthony (Box A-92, Folder 132)
    - Paige, Beverly J. (Box A-92, Folder 133)
    - Paige, Kent (Box A-92, Folder 134)
    - Paige, Myles (Judge) (Box A-92, Folder 135)
      Photographer if identified: Ace Creative Photos, Alex Hamilton
    - Paige, Myles A. (Judge) (Box A-92, Folder 136)
      Bio information and speech by Ralph Bunche
    - Paige, Satchel (Box A-92, Folder 137)
    - Paine, George (Box A-92, Folder 138)
    - Paine, Wingate Mrs. (Box A-92, Folder 139)
    - Pair, Dr. (Box A-92, Folder 140)
      Photographer if identified: Bill Carter
    - Pair, Hermine (Box A-92, Folder 141)
    - Paisner, Claire (Box A-92, Folder 142)
      Also one velox print. 1 print taped to cardboard.
      Photographer if identified: Photography by Wilson
    - P. A. L. (See Police Athletic League) (Box A-92, Folder 143)
      Photographer if identified: Photos by Luigi, Pictorial Enterprise
    - Palemine, Rose (Box A-92, Folder 144)
      Staple through edge of print.
    - Paley, Petronia (Box A-92, Folder 145)
    - Palin, Pati (Box A-92, Folder 146)
    - Palmer's (Box A-92, Folder 147)
    - Palmer, Clarice (Box A-92, Folder 148)
      Photographer if identified: Harris Photo, James Gilbert, Gilbert Pictorial Enterprise
      Number of Prints: 5
    - Palmer, Don Dr. (Box A-92, Folder 149)
    - Dr. Doreen Palmer (Box A-92, Folder 150)
    - Palmer, Edward (Box A-92, Folder 151)
      Photographer if identified: A. Hansen
    - Palmer, Francine (Box A-92, Folder 152)
      Photographer if identified: Larry Brown
    - Palmer, George Mrs. (Box A-92, Folder 153)
    - Palmer, Grayce (Box A-92, Folder 154)
    - Palmer, Jeree (Box A-92, Folder 155)
    - Palmer, Jesse (Negro History Winners) (Box A-92, Folder 156)
      Photographer if identified: Rufus Merritt, Harris Photo
    - Palmer, Joan (Box A-92, Folder 157)
    - Palmer, John (Box A-92, Folder 158)
      Photographer if identified: Earl M. Silver
    - Palmer, Joni (Box A-92, Folder 159)
    - Palmer, Larry (Box A-92, Folder 160)
    - Palmer, Libby (Box A-92, Folder 161)
    - Palmer, Margaret (Box A-92, Folder 162)
    - Palmer, Norman (Box A-92, Folder 163)
    - Palmer, Noel (Box A-92, Folder 164)
      Also 2 velox prints. 1 print taped to cardboard.
      Photographer if identified: Channel 21
    - Palmer, Opal (Box A-92, Folder 165)
    - Palmer, Dr. Robert (Box A-92, Folder 166)
    - Palmer Sisters (Debbie & Joan) (Box A-92, Folder 167)
    - Palmer, Wm. (Box A-92, Folder 168)
      Photographer if identified: Pictorial Enterprise
    - Palmer, William S. (Box A-92, Folder 169)
      Photographer if identified: Cecil Layne
    - Palmerstown (Box A-92, Folder 170)
    - Palmieri, Eddie (Box A-92, Folder 171)
    - Palmieri, Eddie (Box A-92, Folder 172)
    - Palmore, Gayle Miss (Box A-92, Folder 173)
    - Palomino, Robert K. (Box A-92, Folder 174)
    - Pamfile, Josephine (Box A-92, Folder 175)
    - Pan-African Congress (Box A-92, Folder 176)
    - Pan Am Jets (Box A-92, Folder 177)
    - Panama, Francis (Box A-92, Folder 178)
    - Panama, Joe (Box A-92, Folder 179)
    - Panamanians (Box A-92, Folder 180)
    - Panday, Basdeo Senator (Box A-92, Folder 181)
      Photographer if identified: Trinidad Express Newspapers
    - Pandya, Harish (Box A-92, Folder 182)
    - Pan-Hellenic CouncilInc (Box A-92, Folder 183)
    - Panker, Curtis (Box A-92, Folder 184)
    - Pankow, Bernard Rev. (Box A-92, Folder 185)
    - Pannell, Patrick (Box A-92, Folder 186)
    - Pannell, Tyrone S. (Box A-92, Folder 187)
    - Panter, Percival (Box A-92, Folder 188)
    - Panther Attorneys and Supporters (Box A-92, Folder 189)
      Photographer if identified: Harris Photo, Wide World Photos,
    - Panther Shootout (Box A-92, Folder 190)
      Photographer if identified: Wide World Photos, Harris Photo
    - Pontin, Archbishop of Trinidad (Box A-92, Folder 191)
      Photographer if identified: James Gilbert
    - Papp, Joseph (Box A-92, Folder 192)
    - Paradise Baptist Church (Box A-92, Folder 193)
      Photographer if identified: Bro. David McAdams
    - Paradiso, Anthony (Box A-92, Folder 194)
      Photographer if identified: Bill Price
    - Paragon Progressive Community Assn. (Box A-92, Folder 195)
      Photographer if identified: Dave Greene, Bill Price
    - Paramananda, Swami (Box A-92, Folder 196)
    - Paret, Benny (Kid) (Box A-92, Folder 197)
    - Paret-Griffiths Fight 3-24-62 (Benny Paret - Emile Griffiths) (Box A-92, Folder 198)
    - Parham, Esther (Box A-92, Folder 199)
      1 print has press release stapled to recto.
    - Parham, Esther (Box A-92, Folder 200)
    - Parham, John (Box A-92, Folder 201)
      Photographer if identified: News Voice International
    - Parham, Johnny E. (Jr.) (Box A-92, Folder 202)
      Photographer if identified: Ed Bagwell
    - Parham, Martin (Box A-92, Folder 203)
    - Parham, Peggy (Box A-92, Folder 204)
    - Parham, Robert (Box A-92, Folder 205)
    - Parham, Samuel H. (Box A-92, Folder 206)
      Photographer if identified: Cassar Studios
    - Parham, Thomas Capt. (Box A-92, Folder 207)
      Photographer if identified: James E. Markham, Jerry Atchison, J. R. Kimmons,
    - Paris, Crystal (Box A-92, Folder 208)
    - Paris, Freddie (Box A-92, Folder 209)
    - Paris, Lorna C. (Box A-92, Folder 210)
    - Paris, Paul (Box A-92, Folder 211)
    - Paris, Wendell (Box A-92, Folder 212)
    - Park, John (Box A-92, Folder 213)
    - Parke, Jimmie (Box A-92, Folder 214)
    - Parker, Arona (Box A-92, Folder 215)
    - Parker, Audrey (Box A-92, Folder 216)
    - Parker, Barrington (Box A-92, Folder 217)
      Photographer if identified: Bill Anderson
    - Parker, Bennie (Box A-92, Folder 218)
    - Parker, Betty Jane (Omega Queen) (Box A-92, Folder 219)
    - Parker, Bobby (Box A-92, Folder 220)
    - Parker, Dave (Box A-92, Folder 221)
      Also 2 velox prints, 2 halftone prints.
      Photographer if identified: United Press International
    - Parker, C. Eleanor Ms. (Box A-92, Folder 222)
    - Parker, Carl (See Benjamin Goins) (Box A-92, Folder 223)
    - Parker, Charlie (Box A-92, Folder 224)
    - Parker, Cora Elaine (Box A-92, Folder 225)
      Photographer if identified: Harris Photo, A. Hansen
    - Parker, Dave (Box A-92, Folder 226)
    - Parker, David (Box A-92, Folder 227)
      Photographer if identified: Gill Photographers,
    - Parker, David Rev. (Box A-92, Folder 228)
      Photographer if identified: Armando Montezuma
    - Parker, David H. (Box A-92, Folder 229)
      Prints stuck together.
    - Parker, Deirdre K. (Box A-92, Folder 230)
    - Parker, Edward W. Jr. (Box A-92, Folder 231)
      Photographer if identified: Morris Hattem, William French
    - Parker, Elaine (Box A-92, Folder 232)
      Photographer if identified: Harris Photo, Gill Photographers
    - Parker, Elmer (Box A-92, Folder 233)
    - Parker, Ernell (Box A-92, Folder 234)
      Photographer if identified: Rufus Merritt
    - Parker, Eva Mrs. (Box A-92, Folder 235)
    - Parker, Evelyn (Box A-92, Folder 236)
      Photographer if identified: Al Burley, Richardson's Photos
    - Parker, Everett C. (Box A-92, Folder 237)
    - Parker, Gladys B. Mrs. (Box A-92, Folder 238)
    - Parker, Gloria (Box A-92, Folder 239)
      Print has press release stapled to recto.
    - Parker, Henry (Box A-92, Folder 240)
    - Parker, Rev. H. David (Box A-92, Folder 241)
    - Parker, Ida (Box A-92, Folder 242)
    - Parker, Henry (Box A-92, Folder 243)
      Photographer if identified: Miss Luckett, United Press International
    - Parker, Jann (Box A-92, Folder 244)
    - Parker, James (Box A-92, Folder 245)
    - Parker, Janice (Box A-92, Folder 246)
    - Parker, Jann (Box A-92, Folder 247)
    - Parker, Jason (Box A-92, Folder 248)
    - Parker, Jay (Box A-92, Folder 249)
    - Parker, Jefferson (Box A-92, Folder 250)
    - Parker, Jennie (Box A-92, Folder 251)
    - Parker, Jim (Box A-92, Folder 252)
    - Parker, Joe (Box A-92, Folder 253)
    - Parker, John D. (Box A-92, Folder 254)
    - Parker, Jules A. (Box A-92, Folder 255)
    - Parker, Junior (Box A-92, Folder 256)
    - Parker, Dr. L. (Box A-92, Folder 257)
    - Parker, Lenora (Box A-92, Folder 258)
      Photographer if identified: Pope Studio
    - Parker, Leonard (Box A-92, Folder 259)
      Number of Prints: 8
    - Parker, Lola (Box A-92, Folder 260)
    - Parker, Louise (Box A-92, Folder 261)
    - Parker, Luetrelle F. (Box A-92, Folder 262)
    - Parker, Lyman (Box A-92, Folder 263)
    - Parker, Lynne (Box A-92, Folder 264)
    - Parker, Marjorie (Dr.) (Box A-92, Folder 265)
      Photographer if identified: Clifton Cabell
    - Parker, Rev. & Mrs. (Box A-92, Folder 266)
    - Parker, Patricia (Box A-92, Folder 267)
    - Parker, Robert (Box A-92, Folder 268)
      Photographer if identified: James J. Kriegsmann,
    - Rose Parker (Box A-92, Folder 269)
    - Parker, Roy (Box A-92, Folder 270)
    - Parker, Sandra Mrs. (Box A-92, Folder 271)
    - Parker, Sedgewick (Box A-92, Folder 272)
    - Parker, Shirley (Box A-92, Folder 273)
    - Parker, Terence (Box A-92, Folder 274)
      Photographer if identified: NYC Transit Authority
    - Parker, Walter P.H. Rev. (Box A-92, Folder 275)
      1 print has newspaper clipping taped to verso. One print has staple through edge.
      Photographer if identified: Willis E. Allen
    - Parker, Warren (Box A-92, Folder 276)
    - Parker, Warren Mrs. (Box A-92, Folder 277)
    - Parker, William / Mr. & Mrs. William Parker (Box A-92, Folder 278)
    - Parkes, Blanche (Box A-92, Folder 279)
    - The Parkettes (Box A-92, Folder 280)
    - Parkin, Keith (Box A-92, Folder 281)
    - Parking Meters (Box A-92, Folder 282)
    - Parkinson, George L. (Box A-92, Folder 283)
    - Parks (Box A-92, Folder 284)
      Photos of Jacqueline Arnold, Preservation Hall Jazz Band, Calvin Peete.
      Number of Prints: 13
    - Parks, Andrew Curtiss (Box A-92, Folder 285)
      Photographer if identified: Al Burton, Studio Reneé
    - Parks, Anita (Box A-92, Folder 286)
    - Parks, Darlene G. (Box A-92, Folder 287)
    - Parks, Dorothy (Box A-92, Folder 288)
      Photographer if identified: King Photographers
    - Parks, Eddie (Box A-92, Folder 289)
      Photographer if identified: Photographic Laboratory, Marine Corps Base, Camp Lejeune N.C.
    - Parks, George B. (Box A-92, Folder 290)
      One halftone print.
    - Parks, Gordon (Box A-92, Folder 291)
      Also 1 single frame negative in glassine envelope, 1 velox print. 7 prints are stuck together with paste. 2 prints have newspaper clipping taped to verso.
      Photographer if identified: Religious News Service, Cecil Layne, Randy Munkacsi, Harris Photo, Reni Photos, Gilbert Pictorial Enterprise, Walter Daran,
      Number of Prints: 29
    - Parks, Gordon (Box A-92, Folder 292)
      2 prints are stuck together with paste.
      Photographer if identified: Bill Anderson, Gordon Parks, Harris Photo, Sam Siegel, Metropolitan Photo Service, Morgan State College
      Number of Prints: 28
    - Parks, Gordon (Box A-92, Folder 293)
      Also 3 velox prints. 2 prints are stuck together with paste.
      Photographer if identified: Wide World Photos, Brownie Harris,
      Number of Prints: 7
    - Pearl Palomino (Box A-93, Folder 1)
    - Parks, Gordon Jr. (Box A-93, Folder 2)
    - Parks, Henry G. (Box A-93, Folder 3)
      2 prints have staples through edge.
    - Parks, James B. Dr. (Box A-93, Folder 4)
      Photographer if identified: Jules Schick
    - Parks, Lou (Box A-93, Folder 5)
      Photographer if identified: Vogue Studio
    - Mama Lu Parks and her Soul Jazz Revue (Box A-93, Folder 6)
      Photographer if identified: James J. Kriegsmann, Bryan D. Hall
    - Parks, Mark Dr. (Box A-93, Folder 7)
      Photographer if identified: Barbara-Jean Stibler
    - Parks, Marvin (Box A-93, Folder 8)
      One print is a Polaroid.
      Photographer if identified: Jerome Hiler
    - Parks, Suzan-Lori (Box A-93, Folder 9)
      Photographer if identified: Don Parks
    - Parks, Tracy (Box A-93, Folder 10)
    - Parliament-Funkadelic (Box A-93, Folder 11)
    - Parmentier, Louise Miss (Box A-93, Folder 12)
    - Parmore, Robert (Box A-93, Folder 13)
    - Parnell, Jeanne (Box A-93, Folder 14)
      Also one halftone print.
    - Parnell, Sallie H. (Box A-93, Folder 15)
    - Parone, Edward (Box A-93, Folder 16)
    - Parr, Philip E. (Box A-93, Folder 17)
    - Parriott, Joseph (Box A-93, Folder 18)
    - Parris-Anderson Liquor Store (Box A-93, Folder 19)
    - Parris, Bernard (Box A-93, Folder 20)
    - Parris, Canute N. (Box A-93, Folder 21)
    - Parris, Fred (Box A-93, Folder 22)
    - Parris, Fred D. (Box A-93, Folder 23)
    - Parris, Guichard (Box A-93, Folder 24)
      Photographer if identified: Roy DeCarava
    - Parris, Helena (Box A-93, Folder 25)
    - Parris, Ingrid (Box A-93, Folder 26)
      Photographer if identified: Raymond Prentice
    - Parris, James (Box A-93, Folder 27)
    - Parris, Willie Mrs. (Box A-93, Folder 28)
    - Parrish, C. Julian (Box A-93, Folder 29)
    - Parrish, Julian (SEE: Parrish, C. Julian) (Box A-93, Folder 30)
    - Parrish, Corrina (Box A-93, Folder 31)
    - Parrish, Dick (Box A-93, Folder 32)
    - Parrish, Edna (Box A-93, Folder 33)
    - Parrish, Frank P. (Box A-93, Folder 34)
      Photographer if identified: Dave Greene
    - Parrish, Mary (Box A-93, Folder 35)
    - Parrish, Richard (Box A-93, Folder 36)
      Photographer if identified: Whitestone Photo, Alvin J. Burley, A. Hansen Studio, Gilbert Pictorial Enterprise,
    - Parrish, Waldo (Box A-93, Folder 37)
    - Parnell, Virginia (Box A-93, Folder 38)
    - Parrott, William (Box A-93, Folder 39)
    - Parson, Rita (Box A-93, Folder 40)
      Polaroid print with staple.
    - Parsons, Arch (Box A-93, Folder 41)
      Photographer if identified: Adams Studio
    - Eileene Parsons (Box A-93, Folder 42)
    - Parsons, James B. (Judge) (Box A-93, Folder 43)
      Also one paper stereotype matrix. One print has staple through edge.
    - Parsons, Matt (Box A-93, Folder 44)
      2 velox prints.
    - Parsons, Oliver (Box A-93, Folder 45)
    - Parsons, Ralph W. (Box A-93, Folder 46)